

Colton Randall

Postgraduate IT / Programming Student

I am a personable, driven and detail-oriented biochemistry graduate with experience in bioinformatic data analysis. My passion for learning has enabled me to develop a multifaceted skill-set, including recently starting a postgraduate degree in practical programming to enable me to work at the intersection of healthcare and technology.

coltondominicrandall@gmail.com

Auckland, New Zealand

in linkedin.com/in/coltonrandall

+64212517276

coltonrandall.github.io/

github.com/ColtonRandall

EDUCATION

Postgraduate Certificate in Information Technology

University of Auckland

03/2021 - Present

Courses

- Programming for Industry and Web Technologies

Bachelor of Science in Biochemistry University of Otago

02/2015 - 12/2018

Dunedin, New Zealand

Courses

- Advanced Molecular Biology and Bioinformatics

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bioinformatics Research Assistant University of Auckland

07/2020 - Present Achievements/Tasks Auckland, New Zealand

- Project 1: Metagenomics and genome assembly/recovery to improve Aquiluna quality.
- Project 2: Performing molecular dynamic simulations of antimicrobial peptides.

References: Kim Handley (Project 1) kim.handley@auckland.ac.nz -Jane Allison (Project 2) j.allison@auckland.ac.nz

Bioinformatics Research Assistant Manaaki Whenua - Landcare Research

07/2020 - Present

Auckland, New Zealand

Achievements/Tasks

- Reconstructing the evolutionary history of the New Zealand stick insect 'Acanthoxyla' using genomics.
- Genome assembly.

References: Thomas Buckley - BuckleyT@landcareresearch.co.nz

Biochemistry Tutor / Demonstrator University of Otago

07/2018 - 11/2018 Achievements/Tasks Dunedin, New Zealand

- Assisted students during practical laboratory sessions.
- Worked collaboratively to demonstrate and explain biochemical experiments and concepts

References: Kaye Wilson - kaye.wilson@otago.ac.nz.

PERSONAL CHARACTER REFERENCE

Sebastian Dunn, Auckland University Colleague

References: sjadunn@gmail.com

Additional character reference available on request.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming

Java, Python 3, SQL, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, JSON.

Unix

Bash scripting and terminal/command line proficiency.

Research and Data Analysis

Critical thinking and computational analysis of data and literature. Experience in bioinformatics.

SOFT SKILLS

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Volunteer Teacher Elite Visionary High School

06/2016 - 07/2016

Tasks/Achievements

- Successfully designed and presented Math and Physics lessons to a class of 40+ students.

Health Administrative Assistant Kibera Community Health Centre

06/2016 - 07/2016

Nairobi, Kenya

Nairobi, Kenya

Tasks/Achievements

- Helped sick patients gain access to medicine and treatment.
- Aided nurses and doctors in recording important data.

CERTIFICATES

Java Fundamentals - CodeCademy (11/2020 - 12/2020)

Programming Fundamentals (Python 3) - Coursera (10/2020 - 11/2020)

Python 3 - SoloLearn (08/2019 - 12/2020)

HTML, SQL and JavaScript Fundamentals - SoloLearn (04/2020 - 05/2020)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Personal Website Portfolio (03/2021 - Present)

Currently applying knowledge acquired in my postgraduate studies to progressively build my first website that will also act as my portfolio.